G. D. Hsiung papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
G. D. Hsiung papers
1950-2006
Ms Coll 48
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
56
G. D. (Edith) Hsiung was head of the Virology Laboratory at the Veterans Administration Medical Center, founder and director of the national Viral Reference Laboratory for the VA, and professor in the Department of Laboratory Medicine at Yale. The collection includes correspondence, descriptions of her courses and special workshops, presentations, scrapbooks, photographs, reprints of articles, laboratory notebooks, and research manuscripts.
Hsiung, G. D. (Gueh Djen), 1918-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
From the estate of G. D. Hsiung, donated by her grand-niece, Zhe Zhao, Troy, Michigan, through the intermediary of Dr. Hsiung's former student, Dr. John Booss, 2014.
Custodial History
Most of these materials were from G. D. Hsiung's office in the Veterans Administration Medical Center, West Haven, Connecticut.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are generally open for research, but occasional material on patients is subject to review by the Librarian for Medical History.
Biographical / Historical
Gueh Djen (Edith) Hsiung was a pioneer in establishing the field of diagnostic virology. She spent the almost her entire career at Yale and the affiliated Veterans Medical Center in West Haven. Born in Hubei, China, Dr. Hsiung graduated from Ginling College in Chengdu, China. World War II intervened in her plan to attend medical school. After the war, she moved to the United States where she obtained her Ph.D. in microbiology at Michigan State University. She came to Yale in 1953, initially as a postdoctoral student working with Dr. Joseph Melnick on poliovirus and related enteroviruses. In 1960, she was appointed the first director of the Virology Laboratory at Grace-New Haven Hospital. The first of four editions of her textbook, Diagnostic Virology, appeared in 1964. In 1967, she became chief of the Virology Research Laboratory at the Veterans Administration Medical Center in West Haven and a professor in the Department of Laboratory Medicine at Yale. As a result of her initiatives, the national Virology Reference Laboratory of the Veterans Administration was founded in 1985 at the VA Medical Center in West Haven and she became its first director. Through her intensive diagnostic virology courses and workshops in the United States and in Taiwan, she trained generations of researchers. She developed new laboratory methods of cell culture in order to find, identify, and study the behavior of viruses. She also developed animal models, especially the guinea pig, to study viral pathogenesis and test treatments by antivirals. In the late 1980s and early 1990s, she worked on antivirals for HIV. Dr. Hsiung received many awards, among them the Becton-Dickinson Award from the American Society for Microbiology in 1983. She published a scientific autobiography, Mysteries and Miracles, in 1995.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain Hsiung's curriculum vitae; materials related to her awards; correspondence; materials on her courses at Yale and the VA; and documentation of her intensive special workshops on diagnostic virology, including the workshops she gave in Taiwan; the establishment and work of the Virology Reference Laboratory at the VA; scrapbooks mainly from professional meetings and workshops; published articles; manuscript articles; experimental notebooks from her Laboratory at the VA; data and notes on research projects; additional photographs from meetings and workshops; and hundreds of photographs, diagrams, slides, and electromicrographs from her research.
Arrangement
Organized into 11 series: 1. Appointments and General Professional. 2. Correspondence. 3. Yale School of Medicine, Department of Laboratory Medicine. 4. Veterans Administration Medical Center, West Haven. 5. Virology Reference Laboratory. 6. Abstracts, Presentations, and Workshops. 7. Conferences/Meetings. 8. Published Articles/Reprints. 9. Manuscripts. 10. Miscellaneous. 11. Research Materials.
Arboviruses; Adenoviruses; Cytomegalovirus infections; Enteroviruses; Diagnostic virology -- United States; Diagnostic virology -- Taiwan; Electron microscopy; Guinea pigs -- Diseases; Guinea pigs as laboratory animals; Herpesviruses; HIV infections; HIV (Viruses); Leukemia; Leucocytes; Measles virus; Medical laboratories -- Connecticut; Medical laboratory technology; Medical microscopy; Medicine -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Connecticut; Parainfluenza viruses; Poliovirus; Reoviruses; Retroviruses; Virology -- Cultures and culture media; Virology -- Research; Virus diseases -- Animal models; Virus diseases -- Diagnosis; Viruses -- Classification; Viruses -- Identification; Viruses -- Isolation; Viruses -- Morphology; Photographs; Photomicrographs; Scrapbooks; Virologists -- Connecticut; Women in science -- Connecticut; Armstrong, Jane; Bia, Frank J.; Booss, John; Brady, Thomas G.; Chan, Veronica Fernandez; Dowler, Kenneth; Emrick, Robin; Feng, Juesen; Fong, Caroline K. Y.; Green, Robert Holt; Hsiung, G. D. (Gueh Djen), 1918-; Xiang, Jinmin; Landry, Marie L., 1948-; McCormick, Stanley; Melnick, Joseph L., 1914-2001; Michalski, Frank; Nagy, Zoltán; Paul, John R. (John Rodman), 1893-1971; Prusoff, William Herman, 1920-2011; Seligson, David, 1916-; Swack, Norman S.; Tian, Pei-Yu; Tung, Mary Beth; Wang, Jen Ren; Yang, Zhihua; Zheng, Zhi-Ming; American Society for Microbiology; American Type Culture Collection; Hubei Medical College (Taiwan); Michigan State University; Guo li Chenggong da xue; New York University. Medical Center; Pan American Group for Rapid Viral Diagnosis; United States. Veterans Administration; Veterans Administration Hospital Medical Center (West Haven, Conn.); Wuhan University. School of Medicine; Yale-China Association; Yale University. Department of Epidemiology and Public Health; Yale University. School of Medicine. Department of Laboratory Medicine; Interscience Conference on Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy
- Appointments and General Professional, Series I
  - Ginling College (Chengtu, China), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Certificates that G. D. Hsiung graduated from Ginling College in 1942.
  - Michigan State University, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Transcripts from Michigan State College.
  - Copy of Certificate of Naturalization, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital, Manhattan, and New York University, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondence concerning G. D. Hsiung's appointment as chief of the Virology Labratory at the Veterans Administration Hospital in Manhattanand a member of the faculty at the New York University Medical Center. Hsiung returned to the New Haven area when she was named chief of the Virology Laboratory at the VA medical Center, West Haven in 1967. Through this stint in New York, Hsiung retained ties with the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health at Yale.
  - Yale University, 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Appointments and promotions. Hsiung arrrived at Yale in 1953 as a postdocoral student of Joseph L. Melnick, and stayed on. She was then associated with the Section of Epidemiology of the Department of Internal Medicne under John R. Paul, later the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health. From 1960-1965, she serve as head of the Virology Laboratory at Grace-New Haven Community Hospital. After coing back to the New Haven area in 1967, she became an associate professor in the Department of Laboratory Medicine and, in 1974, a full professor.
  - VAMC Research Career Scientist, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Appointments as Research Career Scientist at the Veterans Administration Medical Center, West Haven.
  - VAMC Research Career Scientist, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - VAMC Employment Records, 1965-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - VAMC Performance Appraisals, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - VAMC Retirement, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1979 and 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Federal Woman of the Year Award, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    This was a local rather than a national award.
  - VA Research Career Scientist, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Hsiung was selected as one of twelve scientists in the country for the newly created "VA Research Career Scientist." These were awarded to non-clinical research scientists in the VA system "based upon a continuous high level of capacity and excellence, both in personal research and interactive activities." Folder contains news releases, copy of a newspaper article, and drafts. See also folders 6 and 7.
  - William S. Middleton Award nomination, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Nominations of Hsiung for an award given by the Veterans Administration for a biomedical researcher on the staff. Hsiung did not win the award
  - Becton-Dickinson Award, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Nominations of Hsiung for the Becton-Dickson Award in Clinical Microbiology given by the American Society for Microbiology. See also Box 35, Hsiung's (disbound) scrapbook on the award presented to her at the annual meeting of the American Society for Microbiology in 1983.
  - Burroughs-Wellcome Diagnostic Award from the Pan American Group for Rapid Viral Diagnosis, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Honorary Degree from Michigan State University, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Nominations and correspondence. Hsiung was awarded the honorary degree in 1989.
  - Major Contributions to Research (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Hsiung's own account of her major research interests and accomplishments, 1967 and ca. 1988, and a manuscript "Diagnostic Virology: Half a Century of Research and Development," ca. 2002. Folders 5-20 on awards also summarize G. D. Hsiung's accomplishments.
  - Travel Requests -- Taiwan, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Request to the VA for Hsiung to participate in a Yale-in-China delegation to visit medical institutions in the People's Republic of China.
  - Travel Requests -- Hubei, Taiwan, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Request to the VA for leave to "direct an advanced course in medical and experimental virology in Hubei Medical College in Wuhan, Hubei, People's Republic of China." Includes course schedule.
  - Travel Requests -- Hubei, Taiwan, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Request to attend two virology meetings in Japan and to conduct a virology workshop at Hubei Medical College.
  - Travel Requests -- Hubei, Taiwan, and Beijing, China, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Travel Requests -- Hubei, Taiwan, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Addresses where Hsiung lived from 1937 on (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Materials about Gueh-Djen (Edith) Hsiung (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Includes poems on G. D. Hsiung by John Rodman Paul, 1960, and by Edwin D. Kilbourne, 1988; programs of symposia in G. D. Hsiung's honor for her 70th and 80th birthdays; advertisements for her books; and autobiographical material.
  - Obituaries of G. D. Hsiung, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Includes the program for Hsiung's memorial service at Yale with a brief biography, and a longer obituary by Marie L. Landry.
- Correspondence, Series II
  - People, Subseries 1
    - Anderson, Christine A. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Angeletti, Joseph J. (Jay) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - August, Marilyn (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bailey, David N. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Balkovic, Edward S. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Barr, Charles (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Berlin, Byron S. (Michigan Department of Public Health) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bhatt, Pravin (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bia, Frank (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Brady, Thomas G. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Brozna, John (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chan, Veronica (Institute of Public Health, Manila, Philippines), 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chan, Veronica (Institute of Public Health, Manila, Philippines), 1990-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Chang, Te-Wen (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chen, Bo Quan (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chen, Chun-Ming (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Chen, Hongshan (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Chen, Man (Maud) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Chen, Minzhang (Ministry of Public Health, China) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cheng, Yung-Chi (Tommy) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Chernesky, Max A. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chien, Shu (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Ching, Li (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Chiocco, Doriano (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chou, David Ting-Chao (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Chow, Tina (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Chu, C.M. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Chu, Shih-Hsi (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Costa-Giomi, Patricia (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Crewe-Brown, Heather H. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Deppert, Wolfgang (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dodgson, Jerry (Michigan State University Hsiung-Kimball Scholarship) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Donabedian, Richard K. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Doong, Shin-Liang (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Dowler, Kenneth W. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Drach, John C. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Duan, Shen-Cheng (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Eggers, Hans J. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Evans, Alfred (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Fang, Yi-Lan (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Feng, Chio-Sung (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Feng, JueSun (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Fong-Cheng, Caroline (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Forsgren, Marianne (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Franchini, Genoveffa (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Galasso, George J. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Gonzalez, Aldo (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Green, Robert H. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Gu, Fang-Zhou (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Gu, Zhi-Yuan (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Hirsch, Martin S. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ho, David H. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hsiang, Chin-Min (Hubei Medical College), 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hsiang, Chin-Min (Hubei Medical College), 1983-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Hu, Jian-Ming (James) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Huang, Eng-Shang (Alice) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Huang, Ken-Yen (National Cheng Kung University) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hung, Tao (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Jatlow, Peter (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Kaplow, Leonard S. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Keller, Evelyn W. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Kiang, David (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Kimsey, Paul B. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - King, Chwan-Chuen (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Komolafe, Olumuyiwa O. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Kraiselburd, Edmundo (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Landry, Marie L. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Leary, Jeffry J. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Leu, Jenn-Fuh (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Li, ShiBo (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Ling, Ai Ee (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Lipson, Steven M. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Liu, H. Mei (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Lowe, Nicholas J. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Lu, Bing (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Lucia, Helen L. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Mahafzah, Azmi (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Man, Yan-Gao (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Margalith, Miriam (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mayo, Donald (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - McAllister, Douglas J. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - McIntosh, Kenneth (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Medina, Daniel (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Mellors, John W. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Melnick, Joseph L. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Michalski, Frank (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Miller, Neal E. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Morse, Stephen S. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Murowchick, Robert E. (Yale-China Association) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Myerson, David (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Neumann, Mark A. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Oxman, Michael N. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Palese, Peter (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Planes, Norma (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Plotkin, Stanley A. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Relman, Arnold ( New England Journal of Medicine ), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Richman, Douglas D. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Riker, Donald (Vicks Research Center) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Schneider, Barbara (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Seligson, David (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Shaskan, Edward G. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Shugar, David (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Su, Ih-Jen (National Cheng Kung University Hospital) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Sun, Benjamin (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Swack, Norman (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Tian, Pei-Yu (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Travers, Eleanor M. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Tung, Mary Beth (Lerner-Tung, Mary) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Wang, Ai-Xia (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Wang, Fang (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Wang, Jen Ren, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      General
      Correspondence mostly related to the International Symposium on Diagnosis of Viral and Chlamydial Infections to be held in 1996 in Tainan, Taiwan.
    - Wang, Jen Ren, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Wang, Lin (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Wang, Yng-Fu (Roger) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Winship, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Wu, Hwa-Lin (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Wu, Jium-Shyan (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Wu, Whei-Kuo (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Yan, Jing-Jon (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Yang, Czau-Siung (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Yang, Jiaqi (Hubei Medical College) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Young, Delano V. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Yu, ShuKan (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Yuan, May (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Zeng, Yi (Chinese Academy of Preventative Medicine) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Zhang, Qi-Guang (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Zhao, Lien-San (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Zheng, Zhi-Ming (Thomas), 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Zheng, Zhi-Ming (Thomas), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Zheng, Zhi-Ming (Thomas), 1987-1997 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Zhong-Yuan, Ren (Tianjin Medical College) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Zhou, Ming-Xing (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous A-Z (Box 6, Folder 25)
      Contains letters from: Hoeard Alliger, Sofronio S. Agustin, Jane Bishop, Philip K. Bondy, Jill Crouch, Paul Feorino, Robert J. Fredericks, Richard L. Heberling, Ruth L. Kirschstein,W. T. Liu, W.T. J. Steven McDougal, Frederick W. Miller, Raphael Pappo, D. H. Percy, Paul R. Raymond, Axel Rethwilm, V. Fay Righthand, W. C. Russell, David I. Scheer, Paul Skolnik, Mingquan Suksanong, and Ying Pukang
  - Institutions/Organizations, Subseries 2
    - 302 Hospital (Beijing, China) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - American Association of Bioanalysis (Missouri, USA) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - American Board of Medical Microbiology Exam Questions (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - American Society for Microbiology (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - American Society for Microbiology: Becton-Dickinson Award Committee (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bion Enterprises, Ltd. (Illinois, USA) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Capital Institute of Pediatrics (Beijing, China) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Chinese Society for Medical Virology (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with Tao Hung.
    - Department of Laboratory Medicine, Yale School of Medicine (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Hubei Medical College (Hubei, China) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Hunan Medical College (Hunan, China) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Institute of Materia Medica, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences (Beijing, China) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Lanzhou Institute of Biological Products (Gansu, China) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (New York, USA) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Norman Bethune University of Medical Sciences (Jilin, China) (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Contains correspondence from Zhichao Cai.
    - Pan American Group for Rapid Viral Diagnosis (Box 7, Folder 17)
      Includes correspondence with Stanley A. Plotkin.
    - Peking Union Medical College (Beijing, China) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Research Institute for Tropical Medicine (Manila, Philippines) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Scandinavian Societies of Pathology and Microbiology (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - St. Jude's Children's Hospital (Tennessee, USA) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Veterans Administration Medical Centers (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - West China University of Medical Sciences (Sichaun, China) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Who's Who" Requests (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Wuhan University (Hubei, Taiwan) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Xinjiang Medical College (Xinjiang, China) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Yale-China Association (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Yale University (Professors: Retirements and Honors) (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Honors, named symposia, retirements, and memorial services of other Yale faculty members including Robert M. Donaldson, Jr., David Kessler, Frank Black, Mrs. Young Soo Park, Pravin N. Bhatt, Joseph Bove, Edward Adelberg, Wilbur G. Downs, Elias E. Manuelidis, and Leon Rosenberg.
    - Miscellaneous Institutions/Organizations A-Z (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Topic, Subseries 3
    - Guinea Pig Herpesvirus (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Parainfluenza Type 5/SV5-DA (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Yale School of Medicine, Department of Laboratory Medicine, Series III
  - Virology Courses for Yale School of Medicine, 1969-1987; Subseries 1
    At first G. D. (Edith) Hsiung taught elective courses on medical virology to Yale graduate and medical students. Later she was one of a number of faculty to give lectures as part of the medical curriculum in courses on Infectious Diseases (Medical Virology) and Laboratory Medicine. From 1976 to 1979, she was one of the lecturers in the course on Laboratory Medicine for second year medical students. From 1980 to 1987, she gave the lead lecture in a course on Medical Virology organized by the Department of Laboratory Medicine. Folders contain correspondence, course curricula, her lectures, and laboratory exercises.
    - Methods in Medical Virology, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Methods in Medical Virology, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Infectious Diseases (Viruses), 1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Methods in Medical Virology, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Virology Course, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Infectious Diseases (Viruses) and Laboratory Medicine, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Laboratory Medicine, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Laboratory Medicine, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Laboratory Medicine, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Contains correspondence regarding the 1980 course.
    - Medical Virology Lectures, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum/Correspondence, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Medical Virology Lectures, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum/Correspondence, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Medical Virology Lectures, Part I, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Medical Virology Lectures, Part II, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum/Correspondence, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Medical Virology Lectures, Part I, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Medical Virology Lectures, Part II, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum/Lectures, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum/Lectures, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Medical Virology Curriculum/Lectures, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Medical Virology Laboratory Exercises, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory Medicine Residency Program, 1977-1988; Subseries 2